<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>News / Home on</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in News / Home on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Franciscus' Ode aan de Dieren</title><link>/workshops/franciscus/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops/franciscus/</guid><description>Franciscus&amp;rsquo; Ode aan de Dieren: Songs about Creation and Animal Kingdom from Italian Medieval and Renaissance Music Manuscripts
Target audience: Enthusiasts of all levels
Date: September 30 or October 7, 2023; this will be announced later.
Cost: 87 euros per person
Description: On the occasion of Animal Day, also the feast day of Saint Francis of Assisi, the namesake of our current pope, we work in this workshop on music from the Italian Middle Ages and early Renaissance.</description></item><item><title/><link>/archives/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/news/home/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/news/home/</guid><description>Marsja Mudde Muziek: experienced in giving experience Experienced in giving experience is the motto of Marsja Mudde Muziek and what Marsja stands for as a person and musician. According to her, making music is really an experience profession. As a musician you are trained based on what the teacher experiences while listening to you. And through a lot of repetition and practice with the teacher&amp;rsquo;s feedback, or after a lot of experience, you master the subject.</description></item><item><title/><link>/news/website/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/news/website/</guid><description>Marsja Mudde Muziek has a completely renewed website. The most important goal has been achieved, namely that it now also works well on tablets and telephones and is easy to read. But that&amp;rsquo;s not the only thing that has changed! We hope it&amp;rsquo;s now even easier for you to find everything you&amp;rsquo;re looking for.</description></item><item><title/><link>/zangles/lesagenda/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/zangles/lesagenda/</guid><description>Making lesson appointments Lessons can take place by appointment at my home in Den Bosch, at an additional cost at your home or at another location, or online at a normal rate if desired.
If you want to arrange a lesson or trial lesson, it is best to call or WhatsApp me on +31 6 182 777 92.
I am obliged to comply with the rules of the RIVM regarding the current pandemic.</description></item><item><title/><link>/zangles/methodiek/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/zangles/methodiek/</guid><description>Methodology in early music Methodology of my teachers In my own training Early Vocal Ensemble Music I received input from various angles from my two teachers, dr. Rebecca Stewart and Margot Kalse. I was given directions for interpretation and technical directions to support that interpretation. Gradually it became more and more clear to me how closely interpretation and technique are connected. In fact, in my view, they can no longer be approached separately.</description></item><item><title/><link>/zangles/prijzen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/zangles/prijzen/</guid><description>Prices and conditions Singing lessons at Marsja Mudde Music from January 2023 An ** introductory lesson ** of 5 minutes costs 75 Euro. When a lesson package is subsequently taken out, it will be refunded in part (50% in case of a 5 lesson package) or in full (in case of a 10 or 20 lesson package). When you take out a package of 20 lessons, you will also receive a nice gift.</description></item><item><title>Anime Beatitudinis Cantando</title><link>/ensembles/anime/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ensembles/anime/</guid><description>Anime Beatitudinis Cantando is a professional vocal women&amp;rsquo;s ensemble that breathes new life into the music of the Middle Ages and early Renaissance in a titillating way. The programs are distinguished by idiosyncratic, creative and interdisciplinary total concepts, in which the visible and audible love for this music is combined with texts and images, sometimes also other sensory resources, that together tell a story.
The sound and interpretation of the music by Anime Beatitudinis Cantando is characterized by the fluent following of the original notation, attention to the dialect and accent, attention to the modal harmony and acoustic effects and therefore responding to what the music wants from the singers (and not the other way around).</description></item><item><title>Book "Zicht op Hildegard"</title><link>/products/zichtop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/products/zichtop/</guid><description>Book &amp;ldquo;Zicht op Hildegard; leven, visioenen, geneeskunst, muziek&amp;rdquo; (in Dutch) Hildegard van Bingen was a strong woman with versatile talents, according to the book &amp;ldquo;Zicht op Hildegard&amp;rdquo;, which appeared at the end of 2020. This book is an accessible introduction to the life and work of these twelfth-century Benedictines, after which you will definitely want to go on a pilgrimage to her monastery in Eibingen, Germany. In &amp;ldquo;Zicht op Hildegard&amp;rdquo;, nine specialists shed their light on a sub-area of her life and work.</description></item><item><title>Cantus Modalis</title><link>/ensembles/cantus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ensembles/cantus/</guid><description>Cantus Modalis After her pension in 2007, Rebecca Stewart founded Cantus Modalis, which has both an educational and a performing branch. The main purpose of the educational Center Cantus Modalis is to study and teach the underlying principles of the living modal traditions of the non-Western world in conjunction with the long-dead modal traditions of the Western world, this with the intention of reanimating the Western sense of identification with its modal roots.</description></item><item><title>Civitas</title><link>/programmas/civitas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/programmas/civitas/</guid><description>Civitas Civitas is a project of Marsja Mudde Muziek. Civitas means city and refers to the heavenly city of Jerusalem, the city of peace with a dazzling beauty, but also to the earthly Jerusalem and the many other pilgrimage cities in Europe. In this performance, the stories of a medieval and a modern woman, both on pilgrimage, are intertwined. The medieval woman travels incognito to important pilgrimage destinations throughout Europe and in this way comes to terms with the great loss of her husband and her son.</description></item><item><title>Curriculum Vitae</title><link>/about/cv/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/cv/</guid><description>Medieval and Renaissance specialist and soprano Marsja Mudde (Ridderkerk, 1976) was fascinated from an early age by increasingly older classical vocal music. From the start of her singing studies at the Fontys Conservatory in Tilburg, she specialized in the Middle Ages and Renaissance with Dr. Rebecca Stewart, head of the Early Vocal Ensemble Music department. After her extraordinarily successful graduation concert on Saint Michael and All Angels, she followed many more specialization courses at master level.</description></item><item><title>Die Minne mint ende singt</title><link>/workshops/minne/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops/minne/</guid><description>Die Minne mint ende singt: Medieval Sung Love Poetry from the Netherlands and Germany
Target audience: Enthusiasts of every level; individuals and duos
Date: February 11-12, 2023
Cost: 137 euros per person
Description: In this workshop we work for two days on the beautiful repertoire of the Minnesang, a music genre in medieval Germany and the Netherlands, derived from the music of the French Troubadours and Trouvères. The so-called Courtly Love reigns supreme in this period and inspires many to flowery poetry, which is still inextricably linked to music in this period.</description></item><item><title>Een Middeleeuwse Kerst</title><link>/workshops/kerst/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops/kerst/</guid><description>A Medieval Christmas: Medieval Christmas carols from the Netherlands
Target audience: Enthusiasts of all levels
Date: December 9, 2023
Cost: 87 euros per person
Definition: The feast of the birth of Christ is one of the most important feasts in the Christian tradition, even the most important in the Middle Ages. The music written for Christmas was therefore more often polyphonic in comparison with other repertoire, often had beautiful decorations (melisms, &amp;rsquo;trills&amp;rsquo;, etc.</description></item><item><title>General Information</title><link>/workshops/algemeen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops/algemeen/</guid><description>General information theme workshops for enthusiasts, advanced and (pre-) professionals Below you will find the general information and conditions for the themed workshops. The conditions for workshops for schools and companies are incorporated in the offer.
By who? The themed workshops are all given by soprano Marsja Mudde, a specialist in the music of the Middle Ages and Renaissance. A second teacher may be involved if necessary. You will find information about this in the description.</description></item><item><title>Hildegard von Bingen</title><link>/workshops/hildegard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops/hildegard/</guid><description>Hildegard von Bingen: An in-depth look at the songs of Hildegard von Bingen from the Dendermonde Codex and the Riesencodex
Target audience: Advanced amateurs and (pre-)professionals
Date: date not yet known
Cost: price not yet known
Description: Under the auspices of Centrum Cantus Modalis and in collaboration with Cora Schmeiser, Marsja Mudde Muziek is developing a five-day workshop around the rich repertoire of the abbess Hildegard von Bingen. We will work from reproductions of the original manuscripts.</description></item><item><title>Missa Paschalis Isaac</title><link>/products/paschalis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/products/paschalis/</guid><description>Missa Paschalis ‘ad organum’, a CD from Cantus Modalis In September 2012 the early music ensemble Cantus Modalis made a most special recording in Ostönnen (Westphalia). In addition to a praeambulum by Adam Ileborgh van Stendhal and music for Easter by Guillaume Dufay, Josquin des Prez and Fridolin Sicher, the pièce de résistance was the six-voice Missa Paschalis by Heinrich Isaac (ca. 1450–1517). In this so-called ‘alternatim’ mass, Isaac’s polyphonic setting of sections of the Gregorian ordinary chants from the Graduale Pataviense for the Easter season is heard antiphonally with organ intabulations of the adjacent phrases by Hans Buchner (1483–1538).</description></item><item><title>On the way to Santiago</title><link>/workshops/santiago/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops/santiago/</guid><description>On the way to Santiago da Compostella: Medieval Pilgrim Songs from mainly Spanish Music Manuscripts
Target audience: Advanced amateurs and (pre-)professionals
Date: June 19-21, 2023
Cost: 197 euros per person
Description: When summer arrives, almost everyone prepares for the holidays. In the Middle Ages, too, people traveled a lot and in order to keep pace and sense, they often sang. The journeys made by the Middle Ages often served to visit distant relatives, as a messenger for high-ranking people, as a war path (crusades!</description></item><item><title>Project Devotio Moderna</title><link>/products/gremode/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/products/gremode/</guid><description>Book and cd Gregorian chant and songs from the Modern Devotion by ensemble Trigon The Key2Singing foundation has released a CD and book to conclude the Gregorian Chant and Modern Devotion - Treasure Digging in Our Cultural Heritage project. Last year, ensemble Trigon was commissioned by the Key2Singing foundation to conduct research into the music of Gregorian chant and the Modern Devotion in the Low Countries in the period 1350-1550. In the context of this project, in addition to a study of the history of this music and the original musical notation, various workshops and concerts have been organized.</description></item><item><title>Tailor-made workshops</title><link>/workshops/opmaat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops/opmaat/</guid><description>Customized workshops Marsja Mudde Muziek provides tailor-made workshops for all kinds of occasions and target groups.
Possibilities On request, changes can be made to an existing workshop, such as the location, schedule or duration of the workshop, the number of participants, the precise content or learning objectives, or the target group. But it can also happen that you want to develop a new workshop especially for you or your choir, ensemble, school or work.</description></item><item><title>Vita Hildegardis Bingenis</title><link>/programmas/vita/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/programmas/vita/</guid><description>Vita Hildegardis Bingensis Vita Hildegardis Bingensis is a concert series with the new ensemble Anime Beatitudinis Cantando with the singers Agnieszka Chabowska, Cora Schmeiser and Marsja Mudde. The program is about the life of Hildegard von Bingen with music by this famous abbess himself. In seven scenes, the singers immerse themselves in the world of the nuns led by Hildegard in the 12th century monastery on the Rupertsberg. The audience is treated to titillating vocals and lacks senses to take it all in.</description></item></channel></rss>