<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CDs &amp; Books on Marsja Mudde Muziek</title>
    <link>https://marsjamudde.nl/en/products/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CDs &amp; Books on Marsja Mudde Muziek</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://marsjamudde.nl/en/products/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Book &#34;Zicht op Hildegard&#34;</title>
      <link>https://marsjamudde.nl/en/products/zichtop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://marsjamudde.nl/en/products/zichtop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;book-zicht-op-hildegard-leven-visioenen-geneeskunst-muziek-in-dutch&#34;&gt;Book &amp;ldquo;Zicht op Hildegard; leven, visioenen, geneeskunst, muziek&amp;rdquo; (in Dutch)&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hildegard van Bingen was a strong woman with versatile talents, according to the book &amp;ldquo;Zicht op Hildegard&amp;rdquo;, which appeared at the end of 2020. This book is an accessible introduction to the life and work of these twelfth-century Benedictines, after which you will definitely want to go on a pilgrimage to her monastery in Eibingen, Germany. In &amp;ldquo;Zicht op Hildegard&amp;rdquo;, nine specialists shed their light on a sub-area of her life and work. All in all, this results in a versatile and penetrating portrait.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Missa Paschalis Isaac</title>
      <link>https://marsjamudde.nl/en/products/paschalis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://marsjamudde.nl/en/products/paschalis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;missa-paschalis-ad-organum-a-cd-from-cantus-modalis&#34;&gt;Missa Paschalis ‘ad organum’, a CD from Cantus Modalis&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In September 2012 the early music ensemble Cantus Modalis made a most special recording in Ostönnen (Westphalia). In addition to a praeambulum by Adam Ileborgh van Stendhal and music for Easter by Guillaume Dufay, Josquin des Prez and Fridolin Sicher, the pièce de résistance was the six-voice Missa Paschalis by Heinrich Isaac (ca. 1450–1517). In this so-called ‘alternatim’ mass, Isaac’s polyphonic setting of sections of the Gregorian ordinary chants from the Graduale Pataviense for the Easter season is heard antiphonally with organ intabulations of the adjacent phrases by Hans Buchner (1483–1538).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project Devotio Moderna</title>
      <link>https://marsjamudde.nl/en/products/gremode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://marsjamudde.nl/en/products/gremode/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;book-and-cd-gregorian-chant-and-songs-from-the-modern-devotion-by-ensemble-trigon&#34;&gt;Book and cd Gregorian chant and songs from the Modern Devotion by ensemble Trigon&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Key2Singing foundation has released a CD and book to conclude the Gregorian Chant and Modern Devotion - Treasure Digging in Our Cultural Heritage project.&#xA;Last year, ensemble Trigon was commissioned by the Key2Singing foundation to conduct research into the music of Gregorian chant and the Modern Devotion in the Low Countries in the period 1350-1550. In the context of this project, in addition to a study of the history of this music and the original musical notation, various workshops and concerts have been organized. This has resulted in the CD with accompanying book that was released in 2012/2013.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
