<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Workshops on</title><link>/workshops/</link><description>Recent content in Workshops on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/workshops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Franciscus' Ode aan de Dieren</title><link>/workshops/franciscus/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops/franciscus/</guid><description>Franciscus&amp;rsquo; Ode aan de Dieren: Songs about Creation and Animal Kingdom from Italian Medieval and Renaissance Music Manuscripts
Target audience: Enthusiasts of all levels
Date: September 30 or October 7, 2023; this will be announced later.
Cost: 87 euros per person
Description: On the occasion of Animal Day, also the feast day of Saint Francis of Assisi, the namesake of our current pope, we work in this workshop on music from the Italian Middle Ages and early Renaissance.</description></item><item><title>Die Minne mint ende singt</title><link>/workshops/minne/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops/minne/</guid><description>Die Minne mint ende singt: Medieval Sung Love Poetry from the Netherlands and Germany
Target audience: Enthusiasts of every level; individuals and duos
Date: February 11-12, 2023
Cost: 137 euros per person
Description: In this workshop we work for two days on the beautiful repertoire of the Minnesang, a music genre in medieval Germany and the Netherlands, derived from the music of the French Troubadours and Trouvères. The so-called Courtly Love reigns supreme in this period and inspires many to flowery poetry, which is still inextricably linked to music in this period.</description></item><item><title>Een Middeleeuwse Kerst</title><link>/workshops/kerst/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops/kerst/</guid><description>A Medieval Christmas: Medieval Christmas carols from the Netherlands
Target audience: Enthusiasts of all levels
Date: December 9, 2023
Cost: 87 euros per person
Definition: The feast of the birth of Christ is one of the most important feasts in the Christian tradition, even the most important in the Middle Ages. The music written for Christmas was therefore more often polyphonic in comparison with other repertoire, often had beautiful decorations (melisms, &amp;rsquo;trills&amp;rsquo;, etc.</description></item><item><title>General Information</title><link>/workshops/algemeen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops/algemeen/</guid><description>General information theme workshops for enthusiasts, advanced and (pre-) professionals Below you will find the general information and conditions for the themed workshops. The conditions for workshops for schools and companies are incorporated in the offer.
By who? The themed workshops are all given by soprano Marsja Mudde, a specialist in the music of the Middle Ages and Renaissance. A second teacher may be involved if necessary. You will find information about this in the description.</description></item><item><title>Hildegard von Bingen</title><link>/workshops/hildegard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops/hildegard/</guid><description>Hildegard von Bingen: An in-depth look at the songs of Hildegard von Bingen from the Dendermonde Codex and the Riesencodex
Target audience: Advanced amateurs and (pre-)professionals
Date: date not yet known
Cost: price not yet known
Description: Under the auspices of Centrum Cantus Modalis and in collaboration with Cora Schmeiser, Marsja Mudde Muziek is developing a five-day workshop around the rich repertoire of the abbess Hildegard von Bingen. We will work from reproductions of the original manuscripts.</description></item><item><title>On the way to Santiago</title><link>/workshops/santiago/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops/santiago/</guid><description>On the way to Santiago da Compostella: Medieval Pilgrim Songs from mainly Spanish Music Manuscripts
Target audience: Advanced amateurs and (pre-)professionals
Date: June 19-21, 2023
Cost: 197 euros per person
Description: When summer arrives, almost everyone prepares for the holidays. In the Middle Ages, too, people traveled a lot and in order to keep pace and sense, they often sang. The journeys made by the Middle Ages often served to visit distant relatives, as a messenger for high-ranking people, as a war path (crusades!</description></item><item><title>Tailor-made workshops</title><link>/workshops/opmaat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops/opmaat/</guid><description>Customized workshops Marsja Mudde Muziek provides tailor-made workshops for all kinds of occasions and target groups.
Possibilities On request, changes can be made to an existing workshop, such as the location, schedule or duration of the workshop, the number of participants, the precise content or learning objectives, or the target group. But it can also happen that you want to develop a new workshop especially for you or your choir, ensemble, school or work.</description></item></channel></rss>