<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programmes on Marsja Mudde Muziek</title>
    <link>https://marsjamudde.nl/en/programmas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programmes on Marsja Mudde Muziek</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://marsjamudde.nl/en/programmas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Civitas</title>
      <link>https://marsjamudde.nl/en/programmas/civitas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://marsjamudde.nl/en/programmas/civitas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;civitas&#34;&gt;Civitas&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;../../../images/Hierusalem_Celestis.jpeg&#34; style=&#34;width: 13rem; float: right; margin:1rem&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Civitas is a project of Marsja Mudde Muziek. Civitas means civilization or city and refers to the heavenly city of Jerusalem, the city of peace with a dazzling beauty, but also to the earthly Jerusalem and the many other pilgrimage cities in Europe. In this performance, the stories of a medieval and a modern woman, both on pilgrimage, are intertwined. The medieval woman travels incognito to important pilgrimage destinations throughout Europe and in this way comes to terms with the great loss of her husband and her son. She finds comfort in the music she hears and sings everywhere and in the texts of wise contemporaries, which she reads along the way. The modern woman follows her, centuries later, with a fascination for the same music and the culture in which it originated and developed. Her &amp;ldquo;holy grail&amp;rdquo; is to find out why this music is so comforting and able to bring peace to a (her?) broken heart. Can be booked from now on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sia laudato, San Francesco</title>
      <link>https://marsjamudde.nl/en/programmas/sialaudato/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://marsjamudde.nl/en/programmas/sialaudato/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;sia-laudato-san-francesco&#34;&gt;Sia laudato, San Francesco&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;../../../images/SiaMiniatuur.jpeg&#34; style=&#34;width: 13rem; float: right; margin:1rem&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imagine this: a medieval troubadour, a street preacher, and a circle of devoted brothers and sisters around him — all with songs on their lips. What did the world of Francis of Assisi sound like?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vita Hildegardis Bingenis</title>
      <link>https://marsjamudde.nl/en/programmas/vita/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://marsjamudde.nl/en/programmas/vita/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;vita-hildegardis-bingensis&#34;&gt;Vita Hildegardis Bingensis&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;../../../images/Die Seherin.png&#34; style=&#34;width: 13rem; float: right; margin:1rem&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vita Hildegardis Bingensis is a concert series with the ensemble Anime Beatitudinis Cantando with the singers Agnieszka Chabowska, Cora Schmeiser and Marsja Mudde. The program is about the life of Hildegard von Bingen with music by this famous abbess himself. In seven scenes, the singers immerse themselves in the world of the nuns led by Hildegard in the 12th century monastery on the Rupertsberg. The audience is treated to titillating vocals and lacks senses to take it all in. While enjoying, one learns something about the life history of this Sybille of the Rhine and her time. Can be booked for the whole of 2027.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
